Guide to the Pauli Murray Project Records, 2004-2012 RL.11019
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Pauli Murray Project records
2004-2012
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
John Hope Franklin Humanities Institute
Duke University. Center for Documentary Studies
Archive of Documentary Arts (Duke University)
RL.11019
5 Linear Feet
The Pauli Murray Project is an ongoing project in the Duke Human Rights Center at the Franklin Humanities Institute. It sponsors programs and courses creating documentaries and other community resources about Durham history. The Pauli Murray Project Records include both community projects and oral history projects from undergraduate courses offered by Duke University through the Center for Documentary Studies and the Franklin Humanities Institute.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research, but original audiovisual and electronic media are closed to use. Please contact the Rubenstein Library in advance of your visit to request the production of listening or viewing copies.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Arrangement
Arranged into series: Community Projects, Oral History Projects, and Audiovisual/Electronic Media.
Historical note
The Pauli Murray Project is an ongoing project in the Duke Human Rights Center at the Franklin Humanities Institute. It sponsors programs and courses creating documentaries and other community resources about Durham history.
Provenance
The Pauli Murray Project Records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2013.
Collection Overview
The Pauli Murray Project Records include both community projects and oral history projects from undergraduate courses offered by Duke University through the Center for Documentary Studies and the Franklin Humanities Institute. Contents include various projects documenting Parrish Street/Black Wall Street in Durham, mapping and documenting civil rights/human rights in Durham, the Still Walking for Justice march, and a Brown vs. Board of Education anniversary exhibit. Files are typically arranged by undergraduate student name, and often included audiovisual recordings of oral history interviews conducted as part of a course assignment. Consult the collection guide for more information. All audiovisual materials have been removed to Box 4.
Durham (N.C.) -- Economic conditions; Durham (N.C.) -- Social conditions; Civil rights -- North Carolina -- Durham; Durham (N.C.) -- Race relations; John Hope Franklin Humanities Institute; Lau, Barbara (Barbara A.); Murray, Pauli; Duke University. Center for Documentary Studies; Archive of Documentary Arts (Duke University)
- Community Projects, 2004-2009; 1
  Access Restrictions
  Original audiovisual and electronic records have been removed to the Audiovisual/Electronic Media Series. These items are closed to use. Please contact the Rubenstein Library in advance of your visit to request the production of listening or viewing copies.
  - Wake Up and Listen, 2006; 1
    - Wake Up and Listen: Durham's Black Freedom Movement audio recordings, 2006 Apr. 23 (Box 1)
      Scope and Contents note
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-DAT-0001, 0002, and 0003; CS-0001 and 0002
  - Brown vs. Board of Education 50th Anniversary, 2004; 2
    - Event, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Durham History Center, 2004-2007; 3
    - Planning, 2004 (Box 1)
    - Museum planning, 2006-2007 (Box 1)
    - Museum Without Walls banner photographs, undated; 4 folders (Box 1)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-OP-0005 through 0007.
    - Durham History Center Preliminary Feasibility Study, 2007 (Box 1)
    - Museum Without Walls sketch, undated (Box 1)
  - Parrish Street Project, 2005-2009; 4
    - Documents and clips, 2005 (Box 1)
    - A New Era on Parrish Street: Draft Interpretive Plan, 2008 (Box 1)
    - Parrish Street advocacy, 2008-2009 (Box 1)
    - Exhibit panel drafts, 2008; 12 folders (Box 1)
    - Draft plan, 2005 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous notes, undated (Box 1)
    - Community Forum for Public Art on Parrish Street report, 2008 (Box 1)
- Oral History Projects, 2004-2012; 2
  - Black Wall Street, 2007-2008; 5
    - Student presentations on DVD, 2005-2007 (Box 1)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-DVD-0001 through 0018; RL-11019-CD-0001
    - Black Wall Street exhibit, 2007 (Box 1)
    - Exhibit photographs, 2007 (Box 1)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-OP-0008 through 0019, with photos from the exhibit planning process.
    - Carissa Drauss interview by Lydia Simmons, 2008 (Box 1)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-DVD-0019. Includes transcription of portion; CDS Agreement
    - Hope Tarpley-McCoy interview by Erin Good, 2008 (Box 1)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-DVD-0020; CDS Agreement
    - Dezrick Dixon interview by David Tapke, 2008 (Box 1)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0002. Includes field notes; CDS Agreement
    - Hank Smith interview by Lydia Simmons, 2008 (Box 1)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-DVD-0021; video log sheet; CDS Agreement
    - Jorden Jones interview by Kevin Tolson, 2008 (Box 1)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0003; CDS Agreement
    - Marion McMillian interview by Luke Steinberger, 2008 (Box 1)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0004. No accompanying papers.
    - Blaze the Stage pictures, 2008 (Box 1)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-OP-0021, with pictures.
    - Self-Segregation Forum pictures, 2008 (Box 1)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-OP-0020, with pictures.
    - Nimit Lad interview by Nishant Patel, 2008 Nov. 15 (Box 1)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0005; CDS Agreement
  - Civil Rights Activism, 2005-2009; 6
    - Civil Rights Activism class materials, Fall 2009 (Box 1)
    - Jackie Brown interview by Catalina Hidalgo, 2009 Nov. 6 (Box 1)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0006. Includes field notes; CDS Agreement
    - Maximillano Hernandez interview by Christie Barnes, 2009 Nov. 13 (Box 1)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0007. Includes field notes; CDS Agreement
    - Melanie Stratton-Lopez interview by Kate Van Buskirk, 2009 Nov. 20 (Box 2)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0008. Includes field notes; CDS Agreement
    - Solomon Burnette interview by Kamilah Burnette, 2009 Nov. 20 (Box 2)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0009; 1 CD with powerpoint; transcript; CDS Agreement
    - Documentary fieldwork practicum: Durham's Black Wall Street class administration and correspondence, 2005 (Box 2)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-OP-0022, with class flyers.
  - Black Wall Street, 2004-2007; 7
    - Asa Spaulding Jr. interview, 2005 Nov. 22 (Box 2)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CS-0003. Includes transcription; CDS Agreement
    - Carl Webb interview, 2005 Nov. 8 (Box 2)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CS-0004. Includes transcription; CDS Agreement
    - Ralph Roger interview, 2005 Jan. 9 (Box 2)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CS-0005. Includes transcription; CDS Agreement
    - Elaine Small interview, 2005 Nov. 10 (Box 2)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CS-0006. Includes interview log; CDS Agreement
    - Wade Penny Jr. interview, 2005 Nov. 8 (Box 2)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CS-0007. Includes transcription; CDS Agreement
    - Viviane Patterson interview, 2005 Oct. 27 (Box 2)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CS-0008. Includes interview log; CDS Agreement
    - Bruce Bridges interview, 2005 Nov. 20 (Box 2)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CS-0009. Includes transcription. No CDS Agreement.
    - Harold Moore interview, 2005 Dec. 1 (Box 2)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CS-0010. Includes transcription; CDS Agreement
    - R. Kelly Bryant interview, 2005 Dec. (Box 2)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-MDV-0001 and 0002. Includes interview log; CDS Agreement
    - Charles Cooper interview, 2005 Nov. 5 (Box 2)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CS-0011. Includes transcription. No CDS Agreement.
    - Nathan Garrett family interviews, 1982 Apr. 11 and 1989 July 12 (Box 2)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CS-0012 and 0013. No accompanying papers.
    - Dr. James M. Hubbard and Dr. Linda Hubbard interviews, 2005 Nov. 17 (Box 2)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CS-0014 and 0015. Includes interview logs; CDS Agreement
    - Lucera Parker interview, 2005 Nov. 22 (Box 2)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CS-0016. Includes interview log; CDS Agreement
    - Documenting Durham's Black Wall Street class syllabus, other materials, 2007 Spring (Box 2)
    - C. Faye Keith interview, 2007 Apr. 16 (Box 2)
      Includes CDS Agreement. No tapes.
    - Debra Bennett interview, 2007 Apr. 16 (Box 2)
    - Kemoire Amey interview, 2007 Apr. 16 (Box 2)
    - Stanley Lyons interview, 2007 Apr. 16 (Box 2)
    - William Bell interview, 2007 Mar. 29 (Box 2)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-MDV-0003. Includes CDS Agreement
    - Scott Harmon interview, 2007 Apr. 10 (Box 2)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-MDV-0004. Includes CDS Agreement
    - Nathan Garrett and Farad Ali interviews, 2007 Mar. 19 (Box 2)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-MDV-0005 and 0006. Includes interview logs; CDS Agreements
    - Carl Webb interview, 2007 Apr. 9 (Box 2)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-MDV-0007. Includes CDS Agreement
    - Alice Sharp interview, 2007 Apr. 17 (Box 2)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-MDV-0008. Includes CDS Agreement
    - Malcolm White interview, 2007 Apr. 11 (Box 2)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-MDV-0009. Includes CDS Agreement
    - Ruth Boyd, Margaret Goodwin, Connie Watts, and Eileen Welch interviews, 2004 May 21 (Box 2)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CS-0017 and 0018. Includes transcription. No CDS Agreement.
    - Joy Mickle, H. Michael Spears, Robert Willis, John "Skeepie" Scarborough interviews, 2007 Apr. 11 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-MDV-0010 and 0011. Includes CDS Agreements
    - Final projects and brochures, Spring 2007 (Box 3)
    - Ernest Fair III, 2007 Apr. 11 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-MDV-0012. Includes interview questions; CDS Agreement
    - Raymond Christian, 2007 Apr. 12 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-MDV-0013. Includes CDS Agreement
    - Calvin Brewer, Carl Webb, 2007 Apr. 9 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-MDV-0014 and 0015. Includes tape logs; CDS Agreements
    - Nathan Garrett, 2007 Apr. 11 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-MDV-0016; Includes CDS Agreement
  - Women on Black Wall Street, 2006-2008; 8
    - Julia W. Taylor, 1st Female President of Mechanics and Farmers Bank, audio documentary, 2008 Apr. 20 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0010. Includes script. No CDS Agreement.
    - Two Agents: Rosa Johnson and Elsie Campbell, audio documentary, 2008 Apr. 27 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0011. Includes script. No CDS Agreement.
    - Viola Turner audio documentary, 2008 Sept. 15 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0012 and 0013. No accompanying papers.
    - Ms Bessie Whitted audio documentary, 2008 Apr. 17 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0014. Includes script. No CDS Agreement.
    - Julia Wheeler Taylor, 2006 July 25 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0015; RL-11019-CS-0019. Includes interview transcript. No CDS Agreement.
    - Celeste Dalrymple, 2006 Aug. 17 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0016, 0017, and 0018. Includes interview log. No CDS Agreement.
    - Artelia Bryant, 2007 Mar. 26 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0019 and 0020. Includes interview log. No CDS Agreement.
    - Harold Davis, 2008 Apr. 17 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0021. Includes interview log. No CDS Agreement.
    - Robert Kelly Bryant, 2006 Apr. 8 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0022 and 0031. Includes interview log. No CDS Agreement.
    - Rosa Johnson, Atlanta, GA, 2008 Mar. 29 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0023, 0024, and 0025. Includes interview log. No CDS Agreement.
    - "This is Your Life Ms. Bessie", 1959 Apr. 12 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0026 and 0027. Includes transcript from 2007. No CDS Agreement.
    - R. Kelly and Artelia Bryant, 2008 Apr. 14 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0028. Includes interview log. No CDS Agreement.
    - Ruby Bagley and Juanita Pettiford, 2006 Aug. 1 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0029 and 0032. Includes interview log. No CDS Agreement.
    - Elsie Campbell, 2008 Feb. 23 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0030. No accompanying papers.
    - Megan Moskop's project file, 2006-2008 (Box 3)
  - Civil/Human Rights Heritage, 2004; 9
    - Durham Civil Rights Heritage exhibit, 2004-2005 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-OP-0001, 0002, 0003, 0004 (photo CDs). Includes exhibit text, pamphlets.
    - Durham Civil Rights Heritage project banner exhibit mockups, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Civil Rights Photo Project, 2004 (Box 3)
  - Mapping Durham Civil/Human Rights, 2010-2011; 10
    - Interview with Ann Sink by Emily McGinty, 2010 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0033. Includes field notes; CDS Agreement.
    - Dixie Tauber project file, including her interview of Susie Deter, 2010 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0034. Includes field notes; CDS Agreement.
    - Elijah Brunson project file, including his interview of Kevin Fason, 2010 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0035. Includes tape log; CDS Agreement.
    - Hannah Scott interview of Eric Olson-Getty, 2010 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0036. Includes field notes; CDS Agreement.
    - India Grant project file, including her interview of Michael Palmer, 2010 Nov. 22 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0037. Includes tape log; CDS Agreement.
    - Hannah Cranston interview of Paula Januzzi, 2010 Nov. 18 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0038. Includes field notes; CDS Agreement.
    - Virginia Thomas interview of Philip Azar, 2011 Dec. 3 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0039. Includes field notes; CDS Agreement.
    - Sean Dillard interview of Toka Pearson, 2011 Dec. 11 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0040. Includes field notes; CDS Agreement.
    - Bri Howerton interview of April Johnson, 2011 Dec. 6 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0041. Includes field notes; CDS Agreement.
    - Marcus Benning interview of Aurelia D'Antonio, 2011 Nov. 22 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0042. Includes field notes; CDS Agreement.
    - Liz Hannah interview of Lizzeth Alacorn, 2011 Nov. 17 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0043. Includes field notes; CDS Agreement.
    - Sina Gebre-Ab interview of John Compton, 2011 Dec. 1 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0044. Includes transcript; CDS Agreement.
    - Katie Vo interview of Sarah Ferguson, 2011 Dec. 1 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0045. Includes transcript; CDS Agreement.
    - Leah Elliott project file with her interview of InsideOut, 2011 Dec. 7 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0046. Includes transcript; CDS Agreement.
    - Annie Piotrowski interview of Shaoli Chaudhuri, 2011 Dec. 3 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0047. Includes field notes; CDS Agreement.
  - Still Walking for Justice, 2012; 11
    - Charles West interview of Susan Pierson, 2012 Dec. 2 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0048. Includes field notes; CDS Agreement.
    - Emmanuela Jean-Etienne interview of Virginia Williams, 2012 Dec. 7 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0049. Includes field notes; CDS Agreement.
    - Anshuleena Vipparla interview of Beth Brockman, 2012 Nov. 19 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0050. Includes field notes; CDS Agreement.
    - Ilana Bernstein interview of Vicki Ryder, 2012 Dec. 3 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0051. Includes field notes; CDS Agreement.
    - Rebecca Spicehandler interview of Tomeka Hayes, 2012 Nov. 28 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0052. Includes field notes; CDS Agreement.
    - Taylor Nortman interview of Mary McClintock Fulkerson, 2012 Nov. 30 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0053. Includes field notes; CDS Agreement.
    - Eliza Meredith interview of Ann Atwater, 2012 Nov. 30 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0054. Includes field notes; CDS Agreement.
    - Lindsey Huth interview of Nikole Holland, 2012 Nov. 29 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0055. Includes field notes; CDS Agreement.
    - Mao Hu interview of Quentin Harper, 2012 Nov. 26 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0056. Includes field notes; CDS Agreement.
    - Julijana Englander interview of Barbara Lau, 2012 Nov. 27 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0057. Includes field notes; CDS Agreement.
    - Kaley Deal interview of Mandy Carter, 2012 Nov. 28 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0058. Includes field notes; CDS Agreement.
    - Miranda Curtis interview of Ruth Zalph, 2012 Nov. 30 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0059. Includes field notes; CDS Agreement.
    - Chandra Christmas-Rouse interview of Madeleine Pabis, 2012 Nov. 26 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0060. Includes field notes; CDS Agreement.
    - Kelli Aibel interview of Lynda Berg, 2012 Nov. 26 (Box 3)
      Removed to Box 4: RL-11019-CD-0061. Includes field notes; CDS Agreement.
- Audiovisual/Electronic Media, 2004-2012; 3
  - All audiovisual and electronic separated media, 2000s (Box 4)
    Original audiovisual media and electronic discs are closed to used. Contact Rubenstein Library in advance of your visit to request listening or viewing copies of these materials.